<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pdfxml><content>Form W-4 (2013) Purpose. Complete Form W-4 so that your  employer can withhold the correct federal income  tax from your pay. Consider completing a new Form  W-4 each year and when your personal or financial  situation changes. Exemption from withholding. If you are exempt,  complete  only  lines 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7 and sign the  form to validate it. Your exemption for 2013 expires  February 17, 2014. See Pub. 505, Tax Withholding  and Estimated Tax. Note. If another person can claim you as a  dependent on his or her tax return, you cannot claim  exemption from withholding if your income exceeds  $1,000 and includes more than $350 of unearned  income (for example, interest and dividends). Basic instructions. If you are not exempt, complete  the Personal Allowances Worksheet below. The  worksheets on page 2 further adjust your  withholding allowances based on itemized  deductions, certain credits, adjustments to income,  or two-earners/multiple jobs situations.  Complete all worksheets that apply. However, you  may claim fewer (or zero) allowances. For regular  wages, withholding must be based on allowances  you claimed and may not be a flat amount or  percentage of wages. Head of household. Generally, you can claim head  of household filing status on your tax return only if  you are unmarried and pay more than 50% of the  costs of keeping up a home for yourself and your  dependent(s) or other qualifying individuals. See  Pub. 501, Exemptions, Standard Deduction, and  Filing Information, for information. Tax credits. You can take projected tax credits into  account in figuring your allowable number of  withholding allowances. Credits for child or  dependent care expenses and the child tax credit  may be claimed using the Personal Allowances  Worksheet below. See Pub. 505 for information on  converting your other credits into withholding  allowances. Nonwage income. If you have a large amount of  nonwage income, such as interest or dividends,  consider making estimated tax payments using Form  1040-ES, Estimated Tax for Individuals. Otherwise, you  may owe additional tax. If you have pension or annuity  income, see Pub. 505 to find out if you should adjust  your withholding on Form W-4 or W-4P. Two earners or multiple jobs. If you have a  working spouse or more than one job, figure the  total number of allowances you are entitled to claim  on all jobs using worksheets from only one Form  W-4. Your withholding usually will be most accurate  when all allowances are claimed on the Form W-4  for the highest paying job and zero allowances are  claimed on the others. See Pub. 505 for details. Nonresident alien. If you are a nonresident alien,  see Notice 1392, Supplemental Form W-4  Instructions for Nonresident Aliens, before  completing this form. Check your withholding. After your Form W-4 takes  effect, use Pub. 505 to see how the amount you are  having withheld compares to your projected total tax  for 2013. See Pub. 505, especially if your earnings  exceed $130,000 (Single) or $180,000 (Married). Future developments. Information about any future  developments affecting Form W-4 (such as  legislation enacted after we release it) will be posted  at www.irs.gov/w4. Personal Allowances Worksheet (Keep for your records.) A Enter “1” for yourself if no one else can claim you as a dependent . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . A B Enter “1” if: { • You are single and have only one job; or• You are married, have only one job, and your spouse does not work; or                                   . . . • Your wages from a second job or your spouse’s wages (or the total of both) are $1,500 or less. } B C Enter “1” for your spouse. But, you may choose to enter “-0-” if you are married and have either a working spouse or more  than one job. (Entering “-0-” may help you avoid having too little tax withheld.) . . . . . . . . . . . . . . C D Enter number of dependents (other than your spouse or yourself) you will claim on your tax return . . . . . . . . D E Enter “1” if you will file as head of household on your tax return (see conditions under Head of household above) . . E F Enter “1” if you have at least $1,900 of child or dependent care expenses for which you plan to claim a credit . . . F (Note. Do not include child support payments. See Pub. 503, Child and Dependent Care Expenses, for details.)  G Child Tax Credit (including additional child tax credit). See Pub. 972, Child Tax Credit, for more information. • If your total income will be less than $65,000 ($95,000 if married), enter “2” for each eligible child; then less “1” if you                       have three to six eligible children or less “2” if you have seven or more eligible children.  • If your total income will be between $65,000 and $84,000 ($95,000 and $119,000 if married), enter “1” for each eligible child . . . G H Add lines A through G and enter total here. (Note. This may be different from the number of exemptions you claim on your tax return.)  ▶ H For accuracy,  complete all  worksheets  that apply. { • If you plan to itemize or claim adjustments to income and want to reduce your withholding, see the Deductions      and Adjustments Worksheet on page 2.   • If you are single and have more than one job or are married and you and your spouse both work and the combined  earnings from all jobs exceed $40,000 ($10,000 if married), see the Two-Earners/Multiple Jobs Worksheet on page 2 to  avoid having too little tax withheld. • If neither of the above situations applies, stop here and enter the number from line H on line 5 of Form W-4 below. Separate here and give Form W-4 to your employer. Keep the top part for your records. Form   W-4 Department of the Treasury   Internal Revenue Service  Employee's Withholding Allowance Certificate ▶  Whether you are entitled to claim a certain number of allowances or exemption from withholding is  subject to review by the IRS. Your employer may be required to send a copy of this form to the IRS.  OMB No. 1545-0074 2013 1        Your first name and middle initial Last name Home address (number and street or rural route) City or town, state, and ZIP code 2     Your social security number 3 Single Married Married, but withhold at higher Single rate. Note.  If married, but legally separated, or spouse is a nonresident alien, check the “Single” box. 4 If your last name differs from that shown on your social security card,  check here. You must call 1-800-772-1213 for a replacement card.  ▶ 5 Total number of allowances you are claiming (from line H above or from the applicable worksheet on page 2) 5 6 Additional amount, if any, you want withheld from each paycheck . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 6 $ 7 I claim exemption from withholding for 2013, and I certify that I meet both of the following conditions for exemption. • Last year I had a right to a refund of all federal income tax withheld because I had no tax liability, and • This year I expect a refund of all federal income tax withheld because I expect to have no tax liability. If you meet both conditions, write “Exempt” here . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .   ▶ 7 Under penalties of perjury, I declare that I have examined this certificate and, to the best of my knowledge and belief, it is true, correct, and complete. Employee’s signature   (This form is not valid unless you sign it.)  ▶ Date ▶ 8        Employer’s name and address (Employer: Complete lines 8 and 10 only if sending to the IRS.) 9  Office code (optional) 10     Employer identification number (EIN) For Privacy Act and Paperwork Reduction Act Notice, see page 2. Cat. No. 10220Q Form W-4 (2013)  </content><content> Form W-4 (2013) Page 2  Deductions and Adjustments Worksheet Note. Use this worksheet only if you plan to itemize deductions or claim certain credits or adjustments to income. 1 Enter an estimate of your 2013 itemized deductions. These include qualifying home mortgage interest, charitable contributions, state  and local taxes, medical expenses in excess of 10% (7.5% if either you or your spouse was born before January 2, 1949) of your  income, and miscellaneous deductions. For 2013, you may have to reduce your itemized deductions if your income is over $300,000  and you are married filing jointly or are a qualifying widow(er); $275,000 if you are head of household; $250,000 if you are single and  not head of household or a qualifying widow(er); or $150,000 if you are married filing separately. See Pub. 505 for details . . . 1 $ 2 Enter: { $12,200 if married filing jointly or qualifying widow(er)$8,950 if head of household                                               . . . . . . . . . . . $6,100 if single or married filing separately } 2 $ 3 Subtract line 2 from line 1. If zero or less, enter “-0-” . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 3 $ 4 Enter an estimate of your 2013 adjustments to income and any additional standard deduction (see Pub. 505) 4 $ 5 Add lines 3 and 4 and enter the total. (Include any amount for credits from the Converting Credits to  Withholding Allowances for 2013 Form W-4 worksheet in Pub. 505.) . . . . . . . . . . . . 5 $ 6 Enter an estimate of your 2013 nonwage income (such as dividends or interest) . . . . . . . . 6 $ 7 Subtract line 6 from line 5. If zero or less, enter “-0-” . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 7 $ 8 Divide the amount on line 7 by $3,900 and enter the result here. Drop any fraction . . . . . . . 8 9 Enter the number from the Personal Allowances Worksheet, line H, page 1 . . . . . . . . . 9 10 Add lines 8 and 9 and enter the total here. If you plan to use the Two-Earners/Multiple Jobs Worksheet,  also enter this total on line 1 below. Otherwise, stop here and enter this total on Form W-4, line 5, page 1 10 Two-Earners/Multiple Jobs Worksheet (See Two earners or multiple jobs on page 1.) Note. Use this worksheet only if the instructions under line H on page 1 direct you here. 1 Enter the number from line H, page 1 (or from line 10 above if you used the Deductions and Adjustments Worksheet) 1 2 Find the number in Table 1 below that applies to the LOWEST paying job and enter it here. However, if  you are married filing jointly and wages from the highest paying job are $65,000 or less, do not enter more  than “3” . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 2 3 If line 1 is more than or equal to line 2, subtract line 2 from line 1. Enter the result here (if zero, enter  “-0-”) and on Form W-4, line 5, page 1. Do not use the rest of this worksheet . . . . . . . . . 3 Note. If line 1 is less than line 2, enter “-0-” on Form W-4, line 5, page 1. Complete lines 4 through 9 below to      figure the additional withholding amount necessary to avoid a year-end tax bill. 4 Enter the number from line 2 of this worksheet . . . . . . . . . . 4 5 Enter the number from line 1 of this worksheet . . . . . . . . . . 5 6 Subtract line 5 from line 4 . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 6 7 Find the amount in Table 2 below that applies to the HIGHEST paying job and enter it here . . . . 7 $ 8 Multiply line 7 by line 6 and enter the result here. This is the additional annual withholding needed . . 8 $ 9 Divide line 8 by the number of pay periods remaining in 2013. For example, divide by 25 if you are paid every two  weeks and you complete this form on a date in January when there are 25 pay periods remaining in 2013. Enter  the result here and on Form W-4, line 6, page 1. This is the additional amount to be withheld from each paycheck 9 $ Table 1 Married Filing Jointly If wages from LOWEST  paying job are— Enter on   line 2 above  $0   -   $5,000 0  5,001  -   13,000 1 13,001  -   24,000 2 24,001  -   26,000 3 26,001  -   30,000 4 30,001  -   42,000 5 42,001  -   48,000  6 48,001  -   55,000 7 55,001  -   65,000 8 65,001  -   75,000 9 75,001  -   85,000 10 85,001  -   97,000  11 97,001  - 110,000 12 110,001  - 120,000 13 120,001  - 135,000  14 135,001  and over 15 All Others If wages from LOWEST  paying job are— Enter on   line 2 above  $0  -   $8,000 0 8,001  -   16,000  1 16,001  -   25,000 2 25,001  -   30,000  3 30,001  -   40,000 4 40,001  -   50,000 5 50,001  -   70,000  6 70,001  -   80,000  7 80,001  -   95,000  8 95,001  - 120,000  9 120,001  and over 10 Table 2 Married Filing Jointly If wages from HIGHEST  paying job are— Enter on   line 7 above $0  -  $72,000 $590 72,001  -  130,000 980 130,001  -  200,000 1,090 200,001  -  345,000 1,290 345,001  -  385,000 1,370 385,001  and over 1,540 All Others If wages from HIGHEST  paying job are— Enter on   line 7 above $0  -  $37,000 $590 37,001  -    80,000 980 80,001  -  175,000 1,090 175,001  -  385,000 1,290 385,001  and over 1,540 Privacy Act and Paperwork Reduction Act Notice. We ask for the information on this  form to carry out the Internal Revenue laws of the United States. Internal Revenue Code  sections 3402(f)(2) and 6109 and their regulations require you to provide this information; your  employer uses it to determine your federal income tax withholding. Failure to provide a  properly completed form will result in your being treated as a single person who claims no  withholding allowances; providing fraudulent information may subject you to penalties. Routine  uses of this information include giving it to the Department of Justice for civil and criminal  litigation; to cities, states, the District of Columbia, and U.S. commonwealths and possessions  for use in administering their tax laws; and to the Department of Health and Human Services  for use in the National Directory of New Hires. We may also disclose this information to other  countries under a tax treaty, to federal and state agencies to enforce federal nontax criminal  laws, or to federal law enforcement and intelligence agencies to combat terrorism. You are not required to provide the information requested on a form that is subject to the  Paperwork Reduction Act unless the form displays a valid OMB control number. Books or  records relating to a form or its instructions must be retained as long as their contents may  become material in the administration of any Internal Revenue law. Generally, tax returns and  return information are confidential, as required by Code section 6103.  The average time and expenses required to complete and file this form will vary depending  on individual circumstances. For estimated averages, see the instructions for your income tax  return. If you have suggestions for making this form simpler, we would be happy to hear from you.  See the instructions for your income tax return. </content><content> </content></pdfxml>
